[Music]
organization should prioritize a mindset
of risk awareness and preparedness
across all levels departments and
functions it would help identify Y and
resolve both unknown as well as known
challenges in a productive manner
similarly it's important to build a
thought leadership mindset as it helps
to Foster problem
solving adaptation as well as resilience
to emerging
challenges I would say the importance of
Designing and framing a comprehensive
risk management framework probably based
on global standards like ISO 31,000 goo
basil 3 and whichever the organization
choose to you know uh select the
emphasis should be right from risk
identification
Discovery comprehensive risk assessment
two focus on adapting and selecting
right mitigation
strategies hello everyone welcome back
to Ale Cafe season 2 the strategy Brew I
am arti Ki your host for this episode on
our RIS podcast series
[Music]
in the last episode we discussed various
aspects of business risk and how to make
a strategy to be successful in business
in the current episode we will be
simplifying the often used risk
terminologies and their significance I
have with me Mr Steve duza who is the
chief officer in icsl Lombard who has
almost two decades of experience in Risk
Management Mr Steve is with icsl Lombard
for almost five years welcome Steve on
today's episode I hope today's video
will help our audience to enrich their
knowledge on the risk terms
predominantly being used across the
globe thank you for joining us on I Cafe
thanks Ari for having me over for this
discussion it's my pleasure and I'm
looking forward to this chat I'd like to
begin with by discussing some key risk
terms that have become quite prominent
like grey rhinos black swans and vuka
world can you help us break down these
terms and what do they actually mean and
how do they apply in today's risk
landscape it's a very interesting toping
to begin with the complexity of today's
business environment has indeed led to
the emergence of these captivating terms
let's look at them with some real world
context let's begin with the term wo
covered which signifies volatility
uncertainty complexity and ambiguity
which was coined way back in 1987 by the
US Army but even today highlights how
the complex and interconnected world can
compound risk and create a challenging
environment for
businesses individuals and
livelihoods if you look at these
elements let's look at volatility which
can be best described with the share
market we all know that it carries an
inherent risk of ups and downs
but if you look at the Wix which is the
volatility index the average in the
2010s was around 10 to 14 but moved
significantly higher in the
2020s and even spiked to all the way to
80 plus if you look at uncertainty the
technology advancement specifically the
rapid evolution of artificial
intelligence has led to a certain level
of uncertainty for multiple businesses
if you look at the advertising and the
marketing indust industry there is
uncertainty for the demand for designers
content creators and the overall
traditional marketing
agencies let's look at complexity the
Russia Ukraine war is the best example
of how any form of disruptions in the
global supply chain can create
significant consequences for the supply
of essential Commodities and lead to
complex economic challenges from an
ambiguity perspective the Global risk
that we see because of the regulatory
ambiguity today more than 50 countries
went into record elections and there
were also turmoils in large governments
like Germany France Canada even if we
look at some of the regulations around
the use of cryptocurrencies and
artificial
intelligence let's take an example
countries like El Salvador has embraced
cryptocurrencies while some others like
China has completely banned it there is
also so a concern as artificial
intelligence and the regulations for
governing this is still to be finalized
by most countries now let's look at the
second term black SW black SW events are
unpredictable very high impact incidents
which you can analyze only in retrospect
the 911 terrorist attack is a good
example of a black one event the New
York Stock Exchange and NASDAQ was
closed for 4 days which is the longest
shutdown since the Great
Depression the incident led to an
estimated 40 billion dollars in
Insurance claim which is considered one
of the most expensive events in
Insurance history and if you look at a
broader Global and societal
impact the US launched a war on terror
followed by the invasion of Afghanistan
and Iraq which had significant economic
and Global consequences
now let's look at the third term gry
rhinos gry rhinos a bit different than
black swor
events gray rhos again probable high
impact events but are mostly ignored or
overlooked unless they lead to a
crisis that's exactly what happened
during the 2008 Global financial crisis
analyst and Economist had warned of the
vulnerabilities in the Global Financial
system but policy makers and Fin fincial
institutions continue to ignore These
Warnings when the bubble burst it led to
an cascading Financial meltdown
triggering a global recession massive
unemployment and even the downfall of
some of the largest institutions like
the Leman
Brothers another very popular example I
can think of with recent
terms which is the massive outage due to
the faulty software update by the cyber
security firm
Cloud
strike it led to an outage of
approximately 8.5 million systems
worldwide with a financial estimated
loss of $10
billion more than 7,000 fights had to be
cancelled or delayed there were
thousands of medical procedures which
were postponed or delayed and most
institutions whether financial and other
Industries saw system outages which
impacted their business operations today
we are definitely in a wuka world where
such crisis can come anytime and
organization should be prepared to face
that that was really informative Steve I
have much clearer understanding of these
complex terms now while poly crisis
first emerged in 1970 its relevance has
surged in light in today's
interconnected Global challenges
similarly permac crisis was word of the
year in 2022
you know is reflecting a sense of
ongoing unrelenting
crisis how do you see the evolution of
these terms and how do they each capture
the complexities of the current Global
situation so the term poly crisis was
introduced by Edgard Morin in
1970s but has started gaining attention
recently as we Face complex Global
challenges so what is poly crisis
basically it's an overlap of crisis
leading to a ripple effect so if you
look at the pandemic it just didn't
impact human health but led to massive
disruption in the global supply chain
eventually leading to economic
challenges
globally there were Category 3 floods in
Florida last year with massive
floods property
damages impacting the local economy even
if you look at the Israel Hamas conflict
or the growing tensions in the Middle
East it has led to disruptions in the
entire region if you look at the world
since the last five years maybe since
2020 we are in a constant state of Perma
crisis with significant human economic
and environmental
implications in fact if we look at India
we can take a step back and start with
201617 when actually demonetization
kicked in what we saw was a large scale
impact in India specifically on the
informal sector eventually impacting the
GDP growth rate in
India while things started looking
northwards in 1920 we had the pandemic
which led to a global emergency halting
economic growth
worldwide in 2021 to address the
Slowdown countries across the globe
started printing currency and pumping
money to revive economic growth in in
2022 when the economics growth started
picking up Central Bankers were forced
to increase interest rate to tame
inflation and regulate the money
supply not only that in the beginning of
2022 we also saw the Ukraine Russia War
which again led to increase in the price
of energy and food further escalating
the inflation across
economies since 2023 we've been a
constant state of high interest regime
while some countries have started
reducing the interest rate we still to
reach the growth rates of pre-coded
levels in most economies while these are
some of the prominent
events we continue to see a
manifestation of emerging risk let's
take an example climate risk 2024 is
recorded as the hottest year ever
there have been more than 45 countries
with large scale
floods if you look at Cyber risk which
is rated amongst the top three by global
Business Leaders there has been an
increase of 30% cyber attacks year on
year the cost of cyber
crime is an estimated 8 trillion in 2023
which is anticipated to increase till 11
trillion in 2025 5 and all the way till
15 trillion till 2029 while Genai is a
current problem that we seeing the world
is already talking about Quantum
Computing and its potential to disrupt
the encryption methodologies that are in
use
today while threatening data
communication infrastructure and systems
globally which are the backbone of
today's digital connected ecosystems so
whether it is Perma or poly crisis
what we need today is a more holistic
riskmanagement approach to deal with
these
crisis that was really insightful Steve
you know the kind of examples you gave
about covid-19 the Russia Ukraine war in
order to make us understand about poly
crisis and PMA crisis that was indeed
very helpful thank you for sharing that
uh can you throw some light onto the
strategies which organizations should
adapt to identify and prepare for such
potential
children recognizing that there have
been multiple Black Swan events as well
as gr Rhino events in the past and that
these will continue in the future as
well organization should focus on
building resilient adaptive and
proactive risk management strategies
some of the thoughts that come to my
mind are first and foremost I would say
is building a risk aware and Innovative
culture organization should prioritize a
mindset of risk awareness and prep
preparedness across all levels
departments and functions it would help
identify and resolve both unknown as
well as known challenges in a productive
manner similarly it's important to build
a thought leadership mindset as it helps
to Foster problem
solving adaptation as well as resilience
to emerging
challenges secondly I would say the
importance of
Designing and framing a comprehensive
risk management framework probably based
on global standards like ISO 31,000 goo
basil 3 and whichever the organization
choose to you know uh select the
emphasis should be right from risk
identification
Discovery comprehensive risk assessment
two focus on adapting and selecting
right mitigation Strat
IES another important component would be
ensuring that the risk tolerance levels
across domains are defined and what is
the key risk indicators that need to be
measured so that you get an lead
indicator when you see something going
southwards another important element as
part of the framework should be Horizon
scanning as it's important to identify
emerging risk Trends and
opportunities the third critical element
is scenario planning and stress
tesed multiple was scenarios with
extreme events should be designed and
tested so that you know what can go
around when these things happen the
fourth point that comes to my mind is
redundancy and building diversification
into the strategy it's important to
analyze businesses from a concentration
risk perspective and avoid over Reliance
on a single Revenue stream partner
business operations Etc history has
shown for example organizations like
Nokia we did not see the threats coming
due to concentration risk even today we
can see challenges with the Pharma
industry due to overreliance on
apis if you look at the technology and
the automobile industry its dependency
and the challenges that it faced because
of short supply of semiconductor chips
the next point that comes to my mind is
importance for organizations to invest
in early Warning
Systems data is the new oil or the gold
in fact they say a data can speak to you
if you're listening it's important to
organizations to use some of the latest
technologies that are available today
like AI ml so that you can build on your
data analytic capabilities which can
help you detect weak signals which could
precede Le a crisis and the last point
that I would like to touch upon is the
importance of Crisis management planning
and
testing history says that a crisis will
hit you when you least expect it to
happen the difference between a market
leader and the others would be the
organization's ability to face those
challenges and come back to business in
the shortest and the most efficient
manner and hence it's important for
organizations to regularly test their
business continuity disaster recovery
and other crisis management plans in
fact this is a very famous saying by
Malcolm X the future belongs to those
who prepare for it today thank you so
much Steve uh for shedding light on
these complex terms and the current risk
environment I appreciate our viewers for
joining us today I hope all of you have
found this discussion insightful and
engaging as we wrapup I'd like to give
you a sneak peek into our next episode
where we will delve into the risk
management Frameworks and effective
strategies to sail through the multiple
crisis we all are facing effective risk
management is vital and we are excited
to share some invaluable insights from
our leading experts in the field be sure
to tune in you won't want to miss it
thank you
oh